Soumaya Mahdi

Fullstack Developer

Address: Discovery Gardens - Dubai

Phone: +971 50 581 8406

Email: soumaya.mahdi95@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Soumaya Mahdi

GitHub: Soumaya Mahdi

SKILLS AND PROFICIENCIES

- HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, Bootstrap,
 Hypertext Preprocessor (PHP), JavaScript,
 ReactJS, Asynchronous JavaScript and
 XML (AJAX), jQuery, WordPress, Google
 Cloud Platform (GCP), SQL, GitHub,
 Model-View-Controller (MVC), Nextjs.
- Web development, front and back-end development, website content management.
- Teamwork, multitasking, attention to detail, fast learning.
- Deep knowledge in: Python, C language.

LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Native)
- English: Professional working proficiency
- French (B1 Certificate): Limited working proficiency

I'm a Web developer with an ability for creating elegant solutions in the least amount of time, a 4+ year of experience and a great passion for software engineering. Specialized in PHP coding, Google cloud platform (GCP), worked on various projects with frameworks like Next, Laravel and Codeigniter. Familiar with popular CMS like WordPress. Having a wide knowledge in JavaScript (node.js, react.js, nextjs) and expert in MYSQL relational database management systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Full-stack Developer

Freelance | May 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with clients to develop custom web solutions, utilizing Laravel as the backend framework.
- Designed and implemented responsive, user-friendly front-end interfaces using HTML, and CSS and jquery.
- Integrated third-party APIs to enhance functionality and improve user experience.
- Developed and maintained databases, ensuring optimal performance and data integrity.
- Implemented version control and collaborative development processes using Git.
- Conducted regular testing and debugging to identify and resolve software defects.
- Worked closely with clients to gather requirements, provide updates, and ensure project alignment with business goals.

Full-stack Developer

Mekness Commercial Broker | May 2022 - Dec 2022

- Writing well designed testable, efficient code by using best software development practices.
- Scope out, develop, and manage the implementation of new features.
- Create visually appealing websites that feature user-friendly design and clear navigation.
- Assisting with Domain, Hosting and other website requirements.
 Maintain and update websites.
- Troubleshoot website problems and develop new solutions to increase the efficiency of the system.
- Integrate applications that connect data from various back-end services and databases to back-end services using Code Igniter with MT5 Manager API.
- Researching, planning, and implementing new target market initiatives.

Freelanced Software Developer

SISERVS | Mar 2019 - Feb 2022

- Web design and development, social media and website content management.
- Develop user-centrist solutions to increase the efficiency and client satisfaction.
- Client Relationship Management.
- Researches and develops new ways to improve development process.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Masters in Computer and Communication Engineering

Lebanese International University | 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer and Communication Engineering

Lebanese University- Faculty of Technology | 2014 - 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud certifications

- <u>Google Cloud Computing Foundations:</u> Infrastructure in Google Cloud
- <u>Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud</u> <u>Computing Fundamentals</u>

<u>freeCodeCamp certifications</u>

- Front End Development Libraries
- Responsive Web Design

LinkedIn certifications

- Google Ads Essential Training
- SEO Foundations
- SQL: Data Reporting and Analysis

WORK EXPERIENCE

PHP Developer Intern

CPAGrag | Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- · Reporting daily stats about projects and tasks.
- Maintaining servers, websites, and technical devices inside the office.
- Developing and designing landing pages, admin panels and blogs, managing the content of the landing pages.
- Developed, installed, and configured internal applications, as well as new application releases into test and production environments.
- Conceptualizing and developing a library for the company to reduce additional costs involved in using third-party libraries.
- Creating the web-based promotional collateral for different campaigns. Optimizing home and landing pages, also including the agency's own.
- Designing and developing email campaigns with PHP and JavaScript.

Electronic Engineer Intern

S & A S Co Ltd (Security & Automation Systems) | Apr 2016 - Jun 2016

- Completed three-month undergraduate trainee program reporting to my college supervisor.
- Soldering components and repairing circuit boards.
- Monitoring the product line (SMD automatic assembly, reflow soldering, automatic optical inspection, wave soldering.)
- Software download, testing and troubleshooting.